the American submarine blockade had
reduced shipping Imports by over 1
million tons and with oil reserves now
unable to be replenished desperate
attempts were made to make aviation fuel
from pine trees the population 2 was on
the brink of starvation and coupled with
the smallest rice harvest in nearly 50
years the government had resorted to
trying to turn acorns into food the
official da food Russ of 1500 calories
was also not being met with the average
citizen only consuming 500 calories a
day 2/3 below the minimum Japanese
standard those in cities who were far
away from fertile land suffered the most
with Millions traveling into the
countryside each Sunday to barter their
jewelry furniture and anything they had
of value in exchange for sweet potatoes
vegetables and fruit the scko Mizu
report was eventually presented to the
Supreme Council on May 12th with its
damning